[Music]
il cafe we have you covered
a podcast on how technology drives
innovation in the insurance industry
good to have you join us on episode 2 of
isle cafe i'm your host sheetal and the
topic of conversation today is esg and
its impact on the insurance industry our
guest on the podcast is gopal
balachandran chief financial officer and
chief risk officer at icici lombard he's
also a pioneer of excellence in
financial reporting and corporate
governance for india inc now let me tell
you a little bit more about gopal he's
been associated with icsu lombard for
nearly two decades and wears several
hats
he heads finance and accounts investor
relations risk management mid and back
office investments as well as internal
control and loss minimization functions
he was also instrumental in icsu lombard
becoming the first indian non-life
insurance company to be listed and he's
received wider claim and recognition for
his work including awards like the
financial express best cfo of the year
and the ca 400 award in different
categories like risk management cost
management and financial reporting so on
this episode of isle cafe uh gives me
great joy to have gopal tell us about
that which is top of mind for insurance
organizations across the world today esg
thanks so much gopal for joining us on
ielts cafe welcome to the show and how
are you pretty good shital thank you
thank you thanks for that
kind introduction i don't kind of
deserve so much of it but thank you so
much for that well gopal i'm certain
every bit of that is deserved and thank
you for joining us one more time now uh
to get started right esg efforts have
certainly become a significant
differentiator for responsible
enterprises and icsulab clearly a
marquee brand in india the second
largest general insurance company in
india for fy 2022 and also pioneer of
sorts has also demonstrated leadership
in the adoption of esg as part of its
growth strategy so i'd love to hear from
you on that gopal the company's
sustainability goals some of the focus
areas and some of the efforts that have
been undertaken in this regard that's it
that's a great start
so i think when you look at it you
started off by saying that we are the
first non-life
insurance company to be listed on the
stock exchanges in india right given the
fact that we are a responsible
institution
and therefore clearly ehg is something
that
we kind of largely imbibe
as an organization as a part of uh
running the institutions not just for
one or two years but overall several
decades
is how we are looking at
esgs space to kind of embrace as a part
of the way we work
your point on how do we kind of look at
the space
i think honestly i will kind of divide
it into a couple of aspects uh one is if
you look at in terms of what we have
been doing as a company i think we
started off disclosures well ahead of
mandatory timelines of uh reporting in
this particular space just to kind of
give an example
the esg report that we put out publicly
on our website this has been the third
year in the running so that's something
that we have been doing on an ongoing
basis
as you would recollect i think there was
this new mandate which actually is
coming into force from fi 2023
which is the business responsibility and
sustainability reporting requirements
for the top 1000 listed companies now
while this is mandatory for mfi 23 we
thought
given an institution that's largely
responsible and sustainable that's kind
of voluntary adopted it from one year
before
so it is a part of our fy 2022 annual
report we also had a separate section on
the brsr as it is kind of largely known
as an acronym we want to kind of start
ahead of time so that's something that
we have been pioneering in kind of
taking initiatives well ahead of
deadlines that are stipulated for
companies to kind of comply with if i
were to kind of just move forward while
i said that we have been doing the
disclosure on a voluntary basis
but honestly i think the last part of it
is primarily because we have been kind
of able to engage significantly with
multiple stakeholders and when we say
stakeholders it spans across customers
regulators our shareholders reinsurers
our own employees government i think all
of them have been a part of our journey
in kind of getting appropriate feedback
mechanisms so that we can kind of
improve our disclosures better so there
has been extensive engagement with the
stakeholders that we've been doing as a
company
now
while we've been doing that i think
obviously the tone is always set from
the top the board is very very actively
involved we always had a corporate uh
social responsibility committee but in
order to kind of embrace it with the
flavor of sustainability
we also kind of renamed it as csr and
sustainability committee so that kind of
gives a flavor to from the top
the boards are actively involved in the
design and the framework of the esg that
we want to kind of run as an institution
so clearly there is board oversight
that's the third thing that we have been
kind of focusing on
and the fourth piece that i would say is
i think i say again as a company which
is responsible on
effective disclosures
uh as i said this year in fact was the
first year where we also started
disclosing sustainability disclosures
across the various
scope one two and three emissions that
we do as a company we kind of again did
that uh sustainability disclosures for
the first time as a part of the fi 22
more importantly we also were able to
get an assurance done by an independent
and external firm to validate the
disclosures that we put out as a part of
the report that in a sense are those
four or five key pillars
in the way we look at esg as an
organization important takeaway for all
of our listeners i would imagine is that
having a buy-in from the leadership
levels is something that can certainly
drive your esg agenda a lot better the
other thing that comes to mind gopal is
that there has been a growing emphasis
in the larger financial sphere globally
on sustainability for example we've seen
a lot of talk around sustainability
linked loans and other such you know
nuanced approaches
similarly the insurance industry has
pursued sustainability goals in its own
way so what significant tangible changes
do you think they're likely to see in
the insurance sector over the next uh
decade or so okay that's a great
question because we are looking at maybe
the future right so
i'm sure
maybe amongst the audience who is kind
of possibly listening to me
a lot of a lot of them would have
possibly in their minds
are already thinking about the next
vehicle that he or she is likely to buy
should be an electric one right now it
doesn't matter whether two wheeler or
four wheeler but effectively i think
there is a clear need for transitioning
into move to move to electric vehicles
but that's a reality
and clearly we know that electric
vehicles are relatively far better in so
far as
promoting this sustainability theme is
concerned and in that regard i think
from an iss a longboard standpoint
we have been pioneers in providing
insurance solutions for this transition
to electric vehicles mobility uh just
kind of put some data points in the
table
on the electric vehicle space i mean for
the just the quarter that had kind of
gone by
on the private car side we roughly had a
market share of over almost 14
and on the two-wheeler space which we
think will kind of largely transition
faster into adoption of uh ev
there we have a substantial market share
of almost 65 percent uh the number is
quite high at this point of time though
over a period of time we believe it
could get moderated so but that's one
area where we want to kind of see
ourselves taking the lead and possibly
offering insurance solutions on the
electric vehicles segment so that's one
yeah the other area i'm sure all of us
will be kind of
looking forward to kind of see our
entire power consumptions
getting moved into solar power
or renewable forms of energy
consumptions there again i think we have
been pioneers in that space of being
able to offer insurance solutions to
some of these capabilities
and that's again a segment that has done
very well for us so as a company as a
responsible institution
we would want to see how we can partner
some of these corporates or institutions
to be able to transition into some of
the sustainability themes that they
would be kind of working towards right
so that's one area which i would say
in terms of how one can look forward the
second
what we have seen in the last couple of
years particularly during the
kobit uh environment
all of us clearly learned how to work
digital
that obviously means
across the spectrum of your operations
you could see increased adoption of
digital slash technology and that by
itself is going to kind of lend a
significant amount in so far as
promoting sustainability is concerned
because we are all going to see maybe
reduced consumption of maybe paper
travel
reduction of footprint and so on and so
forth
so clearly that's going to be an area
which
we like to see for the future
and the third area again i would say
from an
insurance company standpoint uh an area
which we would be significantly focusing
on is responsible investments uh there
again today from a nice longboard
standpoint we already have a
responsible investing framework
which is largely based on the principles
of un principles of responsible
investing
where we look at maybe getting insights
from investing companies in the way how
they are
promoting sustainability
we do have an exclusion list
in terms of
assets where we want to kind of make our
investments in so clearly i think
both on offering insurance solutions
which kind of
takes care of responsible underwriting
and at the same time responsible
enrichments is equally a theme that
we're working on now you spoke of
technology but it would be remiss of me
to not dwell a little bit more gopal
because we know that technology oh what
can we do without it now right
but uh i'm quite certain that icic
alumni has taken it to another level uh
from the point of view how you've
leveraged these innovations and also
digitalization what what have we done in
the organization so from our standpoint
i think that when we talk of digital uh
it kind of cuts across the entire
spectrum of the wavy source policies
that really service our
claim proposition
and more importantly the way we kind of
digitize our internal processes
that's the way we look at
digital slash use of technology uh
innovation across the various areas that
we operate on
last couple of years we had seen tough
times on kovind environment but over the
last so many years of our operations i
think we have been a firm believer in
technology right let me give you
examples of how we are leveraging
uh technology in in the way we operate
let me take uh
a relatively simpler one motor insurance
now all of us know as and when a claim
happens
we are all in a hurry to get our claims
serviced that's what we want we want our
vehicles back at the shortest possible
time
now there again we take a lot of
initiatives in making sure that we can
speed on the process of survey of the
vehicle
and in the process the customer is able
to possibly get the vehicle back on time
over the last seven years i would say
that we developed
app instaspect app
now what this app essentially does is
when a vehicle goes for survey at the
garage
the garage is able to use the app and
through a live video streaming process
our experienced claim service managers
who is sitting at a remote location
is able to look at the video which is
streaming live
and there is a voiceover that is
happening between the claim service
manager and the garage person
and in the process you are able to
significantly kind of be more efficient
in the entire survey process
this has been a great
enabler for us in
processing the claims much faster
and today
more than 85 percent of our claims that
we settle on the motor own damage side
uses this introspect app and in the
process we have been able to create
customer delight in the way we settle
claims on
motor insurance that's one sample on of
motor even on the policy buying process
many a times customers may tend to
possibly miss
the renewal date so in the process
effectively you may be without an
insurance at the point of expiry of your
last policy
but given the fact that you want to have
a continuing insurance cover
there is a process which is called as
break-in inspection because you would
want to see whether the vehicle was
already having a damage at the time of
the renewal process in case if you have
missed the renewal date there again i
think through the help of technology we
created a app
by which the entire break-in process is
quite seamless the customer can actually
undertake a self-inspection of the
break-in process
and in the process if everything is
clean
it's a kind of a green channel for the
renewal process to happen so there again
i think a very large proportion of our
break-in process is significantly done
through use of digital slash technology
and in the processing customer
experience which is positive
we move to health quickly
if you look at health i think one of the
things again we have been a firm
believer of using uh technology in the
health insurance space as well the il
take care app which is again something
that we created to largely advocate uh
the health insurance proposition though
increasingly we are expanding the
products that we can offer through the
app but that's again a capability which
significantly helps in the health
insurance segment
uh one other example if you're going to
talk about on the use of technology in
the health side is a typical pain point
for a customer
at the time of seeking a cashless
authorization at the hospitals is always
something that we generally get to hear
about
most of us would have faced that for
unfortunate reasons in case if any of us
have to
get admitted at the hospitals there
again the use of technology we
significantly streamlined the entire
cashless authorization process
which used to run into maybe few hours
which obviously is a painful process for
the customer today with the help of
ai ml
mechanisms
what used to take as i said more than
three four hours the cashless
authorization for a select set of
procedures
is down to less than 90 seconds
again i think a clear
innovation that we were able to do on
the technology side
the last time uh you know girish naik
was here and he was telling about the
cool ways in which technology is
leveraged to offer value or deliver
impact to all stakeholders and primarily
of course customers in his particular
case and he spoke about cal scan and i
was like whoa okay you know that samosa
that i'm about to eat you're going to
tell me exactly how many calories it has
and now you're telling me about things
like instaspec it's all fascinating how
you know technology is helping us
achieve this very very important um your
objective for ics lumbar but a lot of
our listeners i'm quite certain you too
gopala must have been wondering why is
shethel asking me so much about
technology and where is the connection
to esg so i'm coming to that now gopal
we need to dwell a little bit more
because here is a country where you are
certainly seeing people getting more and
more comfortable in using tekken
financial transactions and also in their
investment options uh is this an
accurate assessment according to you
what would you say that this adoption
that we talk about by consumers is still
too nascent to actually contribute to
the industry's sustainability efforts in
a sense i'm asking you to connect the
dots between your esg
efforts and technology adoption
when kobe happened i think we all had to
suddenly change the way we had to
operate
uh we have been so used to operating in
a physical world we had to significantly
transform ourselves into a digital world
and believe me
some of these capabilities were already
available with us is just that we did
not want to kind of possibly explore and
make the best use of it
today the way most of the organizations
would like to operate on is an hybrid
environment it should be a combination
of both physical plus digital customers
again have kind of learned
because they are used to availing
different forms of services insurance is
definitely one of them and they have
also kind of migrated themselves from
doing it completely in a physical world
into i would say more hybrid environment
of operating so yes your point is
absolutely right i think the customer
preferences are clearly moving towards
use of technology use of digital as a
way to operate
in our process of sustainability where
we are saying a large part of our
offering will be made available through
the digital means
we see a significant positive adoption
from a customer standpoint as well
that's where when i look at it on the
policy side for example we issue roughly
close to 29 million policies on an
annual basis
of that
97 98 of those policies do not even
enter our office
there is a capability created at the
hands of the customer who is able to do
the requirements on their own
or my internal media or distributor is
able to get it done to the customer
again in a digital form
so clearly i think customer are
embracing
digital slash technology far far better
and in the process as you rightly
mentioned it has been a key enabler or
contributor to the sustainability
initiatives that any which ways we are
focusing as an organization you know
gopal i was just thinking about it a few
years ago you know when there was talk
of driving digital transformation across
sectors and organizations um a lot of
leaders spoke of how this is a function
of culture you need to have the right
organizational culture to drive deity
and i think the same is probably true of
esg as well one of the major hurdles
that organizations will have to overcome
is a lack of knowledge and skills in
their best practices so how does ics
your lombard plan to train and equip its
workforce to understand these important
issues like sustainable finance uh
social and environmental risk management
and also the pivot towards
sustainability as a differential element
in customer value how are we approaching
this now as an organization on the
social responsibility side that's an
area where
our employees actually volunteer for
some of these initiatives
the one is you obviously as an
institution you need to build a culture
to embrace
either social responsibility or esg as a
part of
the way we operate
a lot of our employees have been kind of
volunteering for some of these social
initiatives that we have been running
and they say that we will take the lead
in shaping up some of the agenda for the
organization
clearly there is already a
cultural mindset
in the employees to make sure that they
embrace
social responsibility
on the esg front again we have taken
employees taking the lead on the e part
of the framework i think a lot of our
employees have clearly demonstrated
areas where we as an organization can
kind of look forward for some of those
elements to be kind of implemented they
have done it at their homes they have
done it through some of the social work
that some of them may be carrying out
and clearly they are giving us ideas to
isis lumbar by which we can embrace some
of these elements as a way we want to
kind of promote sustainability so that's
clearly volunteering is one thing that's
kind of
already working as a culture for the
institution
the second is
capability building sessions that we
undertake across the spectrum of the
organization
and more importantly i think we always
keep
kind of pushing our people to say that
why don't we look at something each one
of us can take the lead
in so far as sustainability is concerned
so that's how we kind of largely promote
uh through volunteering initiatives and
to a lot of capability building slash
cultural sessions is what we kind of
embrace us around the nation so perfect
coming together of uh employee
aspirations and organizational
objectives want us to dwell a little bit
more on that s aspect of our esg goals
diversity equity and inclusion uh gopal
and the start of the year i recall a lot
of consulting organizations talking
about how de and i will remain in sharp
focus for organizations and the de ni
ethos in most organizations is something
that contributes to innovation
productivity and also profitability so
the business imperative has been long
established would be great for us to
know what icici lombard's policy is
regarding these important aspects of esg
are inclusivity equity and diversity now
so again that's a great question
and
that's something that's again the need
of the hour
and as a largely spoken
topic
and from an isis lumbar standpoint we
are equally committed on the dei uh
initiative in that regard
there is already a cross-functional
committee that we have created in the
organization
which is primarily responsible for
designing
planning
driving and monitoring the
implementation of the dei interventions
the tone is set from the top
internally
on the gender equity
we already have taken
goals to achieve
over the next let's say three years
across the various verticals across the
various divisions in the organization
each one of them is championing this
agenda of bringing about
gender equity in the organization so
that's one
form of diversity equity and inclusion
the second element is
to also make sure that
today when you look at the entire
working environment uh we need to
embrace people of different work streams
or people who have got different uh
requirements to be able to contribute to
the organizational sustainability
initiatives you need to create more
flexible way of operating for people so
that you get people from different
requirements a part of the
organizational initiatives and there
again i think from an isis number
standpoint we launched flexi working
part-time working
which are all great enablers for us to
be able to get the right set of talent
you can contribute as i said in so far
as the organizational
growth is concerned even in so far as
employee
initiatives are concerned we do carry
out a lot of
annual checkups counseling programs yoga
sessions
so all in all the whole objective is to
make sure that
dei is pretty much a part and parcel of
the organization
right i'm glad you also touched upon
employee well-being as an important uh
you know pillar of all that you are
building for uh the esg strategy at ics
lombard you know gopal now i want to go
back to something that you had mentioned
sometimes i this idea just like jump
goes in my head and then i have to ask
this has got to do with the you know
volunteer work and csr that you spoke of
uh would be wonderful for our listeners
to get a sense of some of these flagship
programs that you might have uh done
which made a big difference in several
locations and communities uh tell us a
little bit about the icsc lombard's
sustainability agenda and csr activities
and how those two come together i think
for isis and lombard
social responsibility is something that
we are quite cognizant of
and some of our initiatives in this
space dates back
almost close to 10 years and the reason
why i'm saying this is we embrace social
responsibility not just to meet the
minimum
regulatory stipulations that came in
some time back but for us
social responsibility is a way of
operating
right to safety
right a problem for us in india today is
we unfortunately a lot of people succumb
to accidental deaths
and the primary reason for some of this
is
for whatever reason helmets are not
being worn
so that's an area where we wanted to
kind of step in and there have been
specifically designed helmets that has
been crafted
for use
again this helmets are being offered not
only to the parent or the person who is
kind of driving the vehicle sometimes
you will also have the child sitting at
the back
so we realized that or maybe there was
also a demand from some of the parents
to say that why don't you also offer a
helmet for the child as well so these
are specifically designed and crafted
the helmets that has been created in
order to make sure
that
the country becomes a much better place
to ride vehicles
and the extent of damage or the extent
of unfortunate deaths
could kind of be significantly minimized
so that's one of the flagship programs
that we have been running as an
organization since the time we have been
doing this almost close to
4 lakh 25 000
lives is what we have impacted as a
result of the ride to safety initiative
if you're going to move away from
let's say vehicle to
carrying hands
a lot of employees of the organization
almost more than 50 of them actually
volunteer to
work on this initiative the whole
objective is to kind of make sure that
children are given a better place to
read we do a lot of
free eye checkups
so that
the problem statement gets detected
ahead of time and in case for some
reason if any of the children needs
spectacles we also make those
practicals available as well
we have impacted more than 3 lakhs 75
000 lives as a part of this
pioneering effort that we've been doing
over the last several years
the third area which also contributes
significantly to sustainability as well
is safe drinking water we call it
niranjali
again we work with schools the whole
objective is to make sure that children
get safe drinking water
and we kind of install water purifiers
at the schools including taking care of
the maintenance of those purifiers
so that's again an initiative which is
very close to us from a social
responsibility standpoint
absolutely as they say miles to go but
then kudos most certainly gopal to you
and the teams involved in all of these
projects for actually making such a
difference in such diverse and yet you
know relevant areas to icici lombard in
the area of csr superb to hear of this
and on a final note gopal one of icici
lombard's mottos if i may add is fulfill
promises responsibly and sustainably how
do you see icsu lombard playing a
leadership role in the insurance sectors
push towards achieving their esg goals
that's a difficult one right because
it's always tough to kind of figure out
how we stay ahead of the curve
in shaping the
elements of future we have generally
taken the lead in some of these areas
for us the first and the foremost thing
that we will obviously stand committed
is the country objective
and there we know clearly i think as a
country they have already committed to
become net zero by 2017 so obviously we
will play a very very vital role in
being able to contribute to that
particular element which will help the
country to kind of commit itself the
second
embracing digital embracing technology
contributes a lot a lot in the way we
kind of promote sustainable way of
operating and therefore even when i said
97 of my policies are sourced digitally
there is still that three percent that's
left left out and can i keep looking at
area by area in figuring out how some of
those elements can be kind of brought
down
third can we step back
and start contributing to the corporates
in figuring out how we can minimize risk
itself in the first place for example a
fire incident fire incident happening
for a particular corporate also results
in challenges from a sustainability
standpoint or let's say from a pollution
risk standpoint
if you are able to meaningfully
contribute or minimize
some of the risk incidences
then in effect you are kind of promoting
or contributing to the sustainability
objectives that's why we kind of worked
on what we call as value-added services
initiative over the last eight years and
area by area we have been looking at
what typically causes a loss or what
typically is a risk that an institution
or a corporate could be facing and in
case if you are able to mitigate some of
those losses
the possibility of a claim gets
minimized which actually kind of is
environment positive
is the way we look at it so vas will
definitely be an area that we will focus
on
and we will continue to look at how we
can be even in our management of funds
be more responsible in the various
investment decisions that we take
so that's one other area that we will be
kind of committing towards end of the
day
employees or people are our asset and
therefore creating
a flexible friendly workspace
and focusing on employee well-being will
definitely be a very very important
agenda in our sustainability
initiatives
superb and you know when i started out
this conversation gopal i realized that
we are going to get some best practices
but i didn't realize that this is going
to be a comprehensive look or insight
into how esg is being realized in a
marquee brand like icsa lombard and for
that we must thank you thank you so much
for walking us through all of these
various aspects of esg breaking them
down into actions and behaviors not just
the level of individuals also teams and
the organization and helping us connect
those dots brilliant chatting with you
and hope to catch up with you again on
ielts cafe thank you for being here
thanks thanks thank you so much thanks
everyone
[Music]
you were listening to il cafe we have
you covered
[Music]